<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A dialogue between a country gentleman and a parliament-man concerning the late King James</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1697</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B08929</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D1292C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R174546</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">64551172</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 64551172</idno>
            <idno type="VID">184523</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B08929)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184523)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2866:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A dialogue between a country gentleman and a parliament-man concerning the late King James</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year 1697.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Sovereign (1685-1688 : James II) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James II, 1685-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="dialogue">
            <pb facs="tcp:184523:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>A DIALOGUE between a Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try Gentleman and a Parliament-Man, concerning the late KING <hi>JAMES.</hi>
            </head>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C. G.</speaker>
               <p>I AM come, Sir, according to Cuſtom and my Duty, to kiſs your Hands, before you take your Journey for <hi>London;</hi> and to wiſh you a Happy one.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>P. M.</speaker>
               <p>Sir, your Servant: But you are ſo good a Husband of your Time, that it is not meer Ceremony which brings you from Home, and you will I Know be as free as formerly, in giving me your Thoughts concerning the preſent Juncture.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C. G.</speaker>
               <p>Whilſt the War, and conſequently the Taxes, were much in my Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours Mouths, and more at their Hearts, I was ſufficiently furniſhed with Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marks upon them; but ſince the Happy Concluſion of the Peace, and the Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal Expectation of ſome Eaſe (eſpecially for the Land) in our Publick Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, all things now go on ſo ſmoothly, that the News Houſes will be leſs frequented for the future.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>P. M.</speaker>
               <p>'Tis very well, Sir; yet 'tis ſeldom ſeen, that after ſo rude a Tempeſt, ſo ſudden and great a Calm ſhould enſue; No rolling of the Waves? No mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mures remaining?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C. G.</speaker>
               <p>Nothing, Sir, of Grumbling that I have met with, and little of Curio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity, unleſs I ſhould take notice of the many wiſe gueſſes my good Neighbours make, what, or whether any Regard, has been, or will be had of the late King <hi>James,</hi> by or after the Peace.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>P. M.</speaker>
               <p>You mean, I ſuppoſe, as to his Support abroad: And how do you find them pray? In good Humour?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C. G.</speaker>
               <p>As little of Reſentment, conſidering how much he had affrighted 'em, as can be imagined. They have yet their accuſtomed Veneration for their Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and would hold it faſt, but that, as they compute a very ſmall matter for a particular ſhare, would ariſe to a handſom Revenue in the Groſs.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>P. M.</speaker>
               <p>They are in the right as to that; and my own Opinion in this caſe would be as little to the purpoſe, it may be, as their Gueſs, having been ſo long out of <hi>London,</hi> and not ſeen Sir <hi>E. S.</hi> in the large Tour he made amongſt his Friends.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>C. G.</speaker>
               <p>A Pleaſant Thing, I thought, was propoſed by a Gentleman you know, which was this: That ſo great a number of Gentlemen, and of the Clergy, having appeared very favourable to the Perſon and Cauſe of their Old Maſter, as they ſtile him, during the War, it might now be allowed by a Law, (paying the common Duties equally with other good Subjects) and they ſhould have leave voluntarily to devote what part of their Eſtates they ſhould think fitting towards his Maintenance. That by this means he would be ſupplied, the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick eaſed, and the Pretenders to ſuch exact Conſcience, Loyalty, and Honour, find an Opportunity of Teſtifying their Sincerity and Fidelity with all the Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plauſe imaginable, and no Danger to themſelves.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>P. M.</speaker>
               <p>Alas, Sir, were it reduced to that, I fear, for all their Zeal, he would often Dine upon Cold Meat. I am yet ſo pleaſed with the Humour, that ſhould ſuch a thing be propoſed, though but in jeſt, I think I ſhould give it my Vote.</p>
            </sp>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the YEAR 1697.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184523:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:184523:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
